Pedro Zanelato

pedeozanelato19@gmail.com | +55 67 99848-2726 | linkedin.com/in/pdrzan | github.com/pdrzan Campinas, SP, Brazil

Summary

Full Stack developer with 1 year of experience in web and mobile development. Worked with many different projects, tools and people always aiming to deliver great products.

Skills

Languages: Java, Javascript, Typescript, Python, C, C++, Ruby

Front-end: Angular.js, Vue.js, React.js, Angular Material, SCSS, Vuetify

Back-end: Spring Boot, Express.js, FastAPI, PostgreSQL

Others: React Native, JUnit, Mockito, Hibernate, Jaspersoft, Docker, Figma

Experience

Full Stack Developer, EducareBox - Remote

Jun 2024 – Present

- Accelerated web page loading times by over 60%, significantly enhancing user experience;
- Refactored a feature notification service leading to a 10x improvement in delivery speed;
- Developed and tested new features for a platform with more than 200.000 users;
- Created robust unit tests to ensure code correctness and maintain code quality;
- Documented system processes and created tutorials to facilitate knowledge transfer and team efficiency;
- Stack: Angular, Angular Material, SCSS, React Native, Spring Boot, PostgreSQL, Typescript, Javacript, Java, JUnit, Mockito, Jaspersoft, Apache Kafka, Amazon AWS, Firebase, Azure DevOps;

Undergraduate Researcher, Algorithm Experimental Laboratory – Campo Grande, MS Sep 2023 – Dec 2024

- Conducted research and mathematical modeling of Vehicle Routing Problems, a class of NP-hard problems;
- Engineered algorithms in C language using advanced techniques to find optimal solutions to the problem;
- Published 3 academic papers detailing novel methodologies, accepted at two national conferences;
- Utilized gdb for debugging, and GitLab for version control;
- Stack: C language, SCIP, gdb and GitLab;

Projects

Chatão

github.com/pdrzan/chatao

- Developed an interactive, real-time chat application enabling instant message exchange;
- Designed application interfaces with the aim to enhance the user experience;
- Implemented user authentication and profile customization features;
- Architected the system using containerization (Docker) and a relational database (PostgreSQL);
- Stack: Javascript, Express.js, PostgreSQL, Vue.js, Sequelize, Docker, Figma;

Fraude Pintada – Pantanal.dev Program

github.com/orgs/OncaPintada/repositories

- Led deatailed data analysis of a fraudulent bank transaction dataset to identify patterns for fraud detection;
- Developed and benchmarked many machine learning classifiers to accurately identify fraudulent transactions;
- Created a responsive web application to visually present project objectives, methodology and results;
- Engineered a real-time transaction monitoring system with a Random Forest model exposed via a FastAPI API;
- Stack: JavaScript, Python, Vue.js, FastAPI, Scikit-learn, Figma;

Education

Volunteering

2023 Brazilian Software Congress

Sep 2023

• Auditorium team member and responsible for helping teachers and researchers make their presentations;

Professor Assistant - Algorithms and Programming

Aug 2023 - Dec 2023

• Algorithms and programming subject monitor and was responsible for assist the teacher, help students and correct tests and projects;